<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE rfc SYSTEM 'rfc2629.dtd' []>
<rfc ipr="trust200902" category="info" docName="draft-dulaunoy-misp-galaxy-format-02">
<?rfc toc="yes"?>
<?rfc symrefs="yes"?>
<?rfc sortrefs="yes"?>
<?rfc compact="yes"?>
<?rfc subcompact="no"?>
<?rfc private=""?>
<?rfc topblock="yes"?>
<?rfc comments="no"?>
<front>
<title abbrev="MISP galaxy format">MISP galaxy format</title>

<author initials="A." surname="Dulaunoy" fullname="Alexandre Dulaunoy">
<organization abbrev="CIRCL">Computer Incident Response Center Luxembourg</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street>16, bd d'Avranches</street>
<city>Luxembourg</city>
<code>L-1611</code>
<country>Luxembourg</country>
<region></region>
</postal>
<phone>+352 247 88444</phone>
<email>alexandre.dulaunoy@circl.lu</email>
<uri></uri>
</address>
</author>
<author initials="A." surname="Iklody" fullname="Andras Iklody">
<organization abbrev="CIRCL">Computer Incident Response Center Luxembourg</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street> 16, bd d'Avranches</street>
<city>Luxembourg</city>
<code>L-1611</code>
<country>Luxembourg</country>
<region></region>
</postal>
<phone>+352 247 88444</phone>
<email>andras.iklody@circl.lu</email>
<uri></uri>
</address>
</author>
<author initials="D." surname="Servili" fullname="Deborah Servili">
<organization abbrev="CIRCL">Computer Incident Response Center Luxembourg</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street> 16, bd d'Avranches</street>
<city>Luxembourg</city>
<code>L-1611</code>
<country>Luxembourg</country>
<region></region>
</postal>
<phone>+352 247 88444</phone>
<email>deborah.servili@circl.lu</email>
<uri></uri>
</address>
</author>
<date year="2018" month="May" day="9"/>

<area>Security</area>
<workgroup></workgroup>


<abstract>
<t>This document describes the MISP galaxy format which describes a simple JSON format to represent galaxies and clusters that can be attached to MISP events or attributes. A public directory of MISP galaxies is available and relies on the MISP galaxy format. MISP galaxies are used to add further informations on a MISP event. MISP galaxy is a public repository <xref target="MISP-G"/> of known malware, threats actors and various other collections of data that can be used to mark, classify or label data in threat information sharing.
</t>
</abstract>


</front>

<middle>

<section anchor="introduction" title="Introduction">
<t>Sharing threat information became a fundamental requirements on the Internet, security and intelligence community at large. Threat information can include indicators of compromise, malicious file indicators, financial fraud indicators or even detailed information about a threat actor. Some of these informations, such as malware or threat actors are common to several security events. MISP galaxy is a public repository <xref target="MISP-G"/> of known malware, threats actors and various other collections of data that can be used to mark, classify or label data in threat information sharing.
</t>
<t>In the MISP galaxy context, clusters help analysts to give more informations about their cybersecurity events, indicators or threats. MISP galaxies can be used for classification, filtering, triggering actions or visualisation depending on their use in threat intelligence platforms such as MISP <xref target="MISP-P"/>.
</t>

<section anchor="conventions-and-terminology" title="Conventions and Terminology">
<t>The key words &quot;MUST&quot;, &quot;MUST NOT&quot;, &quot;REQUIRED&quot;, &quot;SHALL&quot;, &quot;SHALL NOT&quot;,
&quot;SHOULD&quot;, &quot;SHOULD NOT&quot;, &quot;RECOMMENDED&quot;, &quot;MAY&quot;, and &quot;OPTIONAL&quot; in this
document are to be interpreted as described in RFC 2119 <xref target="RFC2119"/>.
</t>
</section>
</section>

<section anchor="format" title="Format">
<t>A cluster is composed of a value (MUST), a description (OPTIONAL) and metadata (OPTIONAL).
</t>
<t>Clusters are represented as a JSON <xref target="RFC4627"/> dictionary.
</t>

<section anchor="overview" title="Overview">
<t>The MISP galaxy format uses the JSON <xref target="RFC4627"/> format. Each galaxy is represented as a JSON object with meta information including the following fields: name, uuid, description, version, type, authors, source, values.
</t>
<t>name defines the name of the galaxy. The name is represented as a string and MUST be present. The uuid represents the Universally Unique IDentifier (UUID) <xref target="RFC4122"/> of the object reference. The uuid MUST be preserved. For any updates or transfer of the same object reference. UUID version 4 is RECOMMENDED when assigning it to a new object reference and MUST be present. The description is represented as a string and MUST be present. The uuid is represented as a string and MUST be present. The version is represented as a decimal and MUST be present. The source is represented as a string and MUST be present. Authors are represented as an array containing one or more authors and MUST be present.
</t>
<t>Values are represented as an array containing one or more values and MUST be present. Values defines all values available in the galaxy.
</t>
</section>

<section anchor="values" title="values">
<t>The values array contains one or more JSON objects which represent all the possible values in the galaxy. The JSON object contains four fields: value, description, uuid and meta.
The value is represented as a string and MUST be present. The description is represented as a string and SHOULD be present. The meta or metadata is represented as a JSON list and SHOULD be present.
The uuid represents the Universally Unique IDentifier (UUID) <xref target="RFC4122"/> of the value reference. The uuid SHOULD can be present and MUST be preserved.
</t>
</section>

<section anchor="meta" title="meta">
<t>Meta contains a list of custom defined JSON key value pairs. Users SHOULD reuse commonly used keys such as 'properties, complexity, effectiveness, country, possible_issues, colour, motive, impact, refs, synonyms, derivated_from, status, date, encryption, extensions, ransomnotes' wherever applicable.
</t>
<t>properties is used to provide clusters with additional properties. Properties are represented as an array containing one or more strings ans MAY be present.
</t>
<t>derivated_from, refs, synonyms SHALL be used to give further informations. refs is represented as an array containing one or more strings and SHALL be present. synonyms is represented as an array containing one or more strings and SHALL be present. derivated_from is represented as an array containing one or more strings and SHALL be present.
</t>
<t>date, status MAY be used to give time information about an cluster. date is represented as a string describing a time or period and SHALL be present. status is represented as a string describing the current status of the clusters. It MAY also describe a time or period and SHALL be present.
</t>
<t>colour fields MAY be used at predicates or values level to set a specify colour that MAY be used by the implementation. The colour field is described as an RGB colour fill in hexadecimal representation.
</t>
<t>complexity, effectiveness, impact, possible_issues MAY be used to give further information in preventive-measure galaxy. complexity is represented by an enumerated value from a fixed vocabulary and SHALL be present. effectiveness is represented by an enumerated value from a fixed vocabulary and SHALL be present. impact is represented by an enumerated value from a fixed vocabulary and SHALL be present. possible_issues is represented as a string and SHOULD be present.
</t>
<t>Example use of the complexity, effectiveness, impact, possible_issues fields in the preventive-measure galaxy:
</t>

<figure align="center"><artwork align="center">
{
  "meta": {
    "refs": [
      "http://www.windowsnetworking.com/kbase/WindowsTips/WindowsXP/AdminTips/Customization/DisableWindowsScriptingHostWSH.html"
    ],
    "complexity": "Low",
    "effectiveness": "Medium",
    "impact": "Medium",
    "type": [
      "GPO"
    ],
    "possible_issues": "Administrative VBS scripts on Workstations"
  },
  "value": "Disable WSH",
  "description": "Disable Windows Script Host",
  "uuid": "e6df1619-f8b3-476c-b5cf-22b4c9e9dd7f"
}
</artwork></figure>
<t>country, motive MAY be used to give further information in threat-actor galaxy. country is represented as a string and SHOULD be present. motive is represented as a string and SHOULD be present.
</t>
<t>Example use of the country, motive fields in the threat-actor galaxy:
</t>

<figure align="center"><artwork align="center">
{
  "meta": {
    "country": "CN",
    "synonyms": [
      "APT14",
      "APT 14",
      "QAZTeam",
      "ALUMINUM"
    ],
    "refs": [
      "http://www.crowdstrike.com/blog/whois-anchor-panda/"
    ],
    "motive": "Espionage"
  },
  "value": "Anchor Panda",
  "description": "PLA Navy",
  "uuid": "c82c904f-b3b4-40a2-bf0d-008912953104"
}
</artwork></figure>
<t>encryption, extensions, ransomnotes MAY be used to give further information in ransomware galaxy. encryption is represented as a string and SHALL be present. extensions is represented as an array containing one or more strings and SHALL be present. ransomnotes is represented as an array containing one or more strings ans SHALL be present.
</t>
<t>Example use of the encryption, extensions, ransomnotes fields in the ransomware galaxy:
</t>

<figure align="center"><artwork align="center">
{
  "meta": {
    "refs": [
      "https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/revenge-ransomware-a-cryptomix-variant-being-distributed-by-rig-exploit-kit/",
      "https://id-ransomware.blogspot.co.il/2017/03/revenge-ransomware.html"
    ],
    "ransomnotes": [
      "https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-KkPVDxjy8tk/WM7LtYHmuAI/AAAAAAAAEUw/kDJghaq-j1AZuqjzqk2Fkxpp4yr9Yeb5wCLcB/s1600/revenge-note-2.jpg",
      "===ENGLISH=== All of your files were encrypted using REVENGE Ransomware. The action required to restore the files. Your files are not lost, they can be returned to their normal state by decoding them. The only way to do this is to get the software and your personal decryption key. Using any other software that claims to be able to recover your files will result in corrupted or destroyed files. You can purchase the software and the decryption key by sending us an email with your ID. And we send instructions for payment. After payment, you receive the software to return all files. For proof, we can decrypt one file for free. Attach it to an e-mail.",
      "# !!!HELP_FILE!!! #.txt"
    ],
    "encryption": "AES-256 + RSA-1024",
    "extensions": [
      ".REVENGE"
    ],
    "date": "March 2017"
  },
  "description": "This is most likely to affect English speaking users, since the note is written in English. English is understood worldwide, thus anyone can be harmed. The hacker spread the virus using email spam, fake updates, and harmful attachments. All your files are compromised including music, MS Office, Open Office, pictures, videos, shared online files etc.. CryptoMix / CryptFile2 Variant",
  "value": "Revenge Ransomware",
  "uuid": "987d36d5-6ba8-484d-9e0b-7324cc886b0e"
}
</artwork></figure>
<t>source-uuid, target-uuid SHALL be used to describe relationships. source-uuid and target-uuid represent the Universally Unique IDentifier (UUID) <xref target="RFC4122"/> of the value reference. source-uuid and target-uuid MUST be preserved.
</t>
<t>Example use of the source-uuid, target-uuid fields in the mitre-enterprise-attack-relationship galaxy:
</t>

<figure align="center"><artwork align="center">
{
  "meta": {
    "source-uuid": "222fbd21-fc4f-4b7e-9f85-0e6e3a76c33f",
    "target-uuid": "2f1a9fd0-3b7c-4d77-a358-78db13adbe78"
  },
  "uuid": "cfc7da70-d7c5-4508-8f50-1c3107269633",
  "value": "menuPass (G0045) uses EvilGrab (S0152)"
}
</artwork></figure>
</section>
</section>

<section anchor="acknowledgements" title="Acknowledgements">
<t>The authors wish to thank all the MISP community who are supporting the creation
of open standards in threat intelligence sharing.
</t>
</section>

</middle>
<back>
<references title="Normative References">
<?rfc include="https://xml2rfc.tools.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.2119.xml"?>
<?rfc include="https://xml2rfc.tools.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.4122.xml"?>
<?rfc include="https://xml2rfc.tools.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.4627.xml"?>
</references>
<references title="Informative References">
<reference anchor='MISP-G' target='https://github.com/MISP/misp-galaxy'>
  <front>
   <title>MISP Galaxy -</title>
   <author initials='' surname='MISP' fullname='MISP Community'></author>
   <date></date>
  </front>
</reference>
<reference anchor='MISP-P' target='https://github.com/MISP'>
  <front>
   <title>MISP Project - Malware Information Sharing Platform and Threat Sharing</title>
   <author initials='' surname='MISP' fullname='MISP Community'></author>
   <date></date>
  </front>
</reference>
</references>

</back>
</rfc>
